Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: MS/M.Sc(Science) [cyber law and

Notice Period: 2 Months

information security]



Consultant seeking roles in ITGC and Application Audit, Information security Audit (ISO 27001), Risk Management, Risk Assurance, COBIT, IT Management, IT Audit, Information Security, Risk Consulting, Change Management, Access Management, SOD Review



Current Designation: Consultant - IT

Current Company: Genpact

Current Location: Delhi

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Delhi / NCR

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Consultant, Risk Management, IT Security Management, IT Audit, Risk Consulting, Change Management, Access Management, System Analysis, Project Management, Technology Management, Information Security, Planning, IT Risk

Management, Application Security, ISO 27001

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

### Summary

Result-oriented Professional with nearly 5 years of experience in Risk assurance and Risk Management, ITGC and Application Audit, ISO 27001 Audit, COSO and COBIT framework, Information Security, Risk Consulting, Change Management, Access Management, Compliance Audit, SOD Review, SOX Complience, Internal and External Audit, Business continuity Management (ISO 22301), SOC 1 and SOC 2

# **Work Experience**

Genpact as Consultant - IT May 2018 to Till Date

- Supported internal IT audit function of US?s 4th largest bank on COBIT 5 framework. Managed the IT COSO team along with leading walkthrough calls and performing Test of Design, Operating and Roll forward effectiveness
- Conducted in-house knowledge sharing sessions for imparting knowledge on basics of IT audits, IT general controls, IT application controls, issue validations and testing documentation standards
- Assisted in documentation and report generation for audits.
- Responsible for Testing and documenting IT general controls & Application controls.

#### T.R. Chadha Co LLP as Associate Consultant

Sep 2015 to May 2018

Working on ISO 27001and SOX-ITGC audit project for organizations as an Internal auditor-

Performed SOX compliance Audit and have assisted IT support audits for Global clients in manufacturing, E-commerce, healthcare, foods and various online travel industries.

Performed Security audit based on ISO 27001 Annexure A controls.

Drafted Security work program checklist against ISO 27001 mandatory clauses.

Performed Application audit and IT General Control Testing of User access management, Change management, Computer operation, Data-backup & Restoration and program development for one of the largest and most challenging

travel online company which is known to have one of the most stringent documentation protocols.

Assisted in drafting Business continuity plan based on ISO 22301.

Drafted controls for an organization based on COSO and COBIT framework.

Performed audit based on Information Technology Service Management.

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=34882c9556a1f9ee84e22011c58711db0b080a071f145f4051164458540...

Assisted in documentation and report generation for audits.

Experienced in direct client dealing both at high-profit large-scale and medium scale organizations. Independently handle complex client with tough deadlines.

Role and responsibilities

Responsible for Testing and Implementing ITGC controls & Application controls.

Creating the Risk Control Matrix for the clients.

Checking the process and procedure for Companies to eliminate the gaps.

Risk Assessment

Risk Mitigation Strategy

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from J K Institute of Engineering, Bilaspur in 2012

PG: MS/M.Sc(Science) (cyber law and information security) from national Law Institute University in 2015

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Diploma in Computer Application Engineering

#### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used Experience	
CCNA, ITIL			
ISO 27001	2013	2017	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SOX Compliance		2018	2 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

### **Projects**

Project Title: ITGC & ISO 27001

Client: EXL

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Sep 2017 - Mar 2018

Onsite / Offsite: Onsite

Project Details: Risk assessment and Risk mitigation

Project Title: SOX-ITGC Client: MakeMyTrip

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Sep 2015 - Jul 2017

Onsite / Offsite: Onsite Role: Other

Team Size: 6

Role Description: Consultant Project Details: Internal audit

#### **Affirmative Action**

#### **Work Authorization**

Category: General Countries: India 1/22/2021  $https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=34882c9556a1f9ee84e22011c58711db0b080a071f145f4051164458540\dots\\$ 

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time